<title>
Nonperturbative Light-Front QCD
</title>

<abstract>
  In this work the determination of low-energy bound states in Quantum
Chromodynamics is recast so that it is linked to a weak-coupling problem. This
allows one to approach the solution with the same techniques which solve
Quantum Electrodynamics: namely, a combination of weak-coupling diagrams and
many-body quantum mechanics. The key to eliminating necessarily nonperturbative
effects is the use of a bare Hamiltonian in which quarks and gluons have
nonzero constituent masses rather than the zero masses of the current picture.
The use of constituent masses cuts off the growth of the running coupling
constant and makes it possible that the running coupling never leaves the
perturbative domain. For stabilization purposes an artificial potential is
added to the Hamiltonian, but with a coefficient that vanishes at the physical
value of the coupling constant. The weak-coupling approach potentially
reconciles the simplicity of the Constituent Quark Model with the complexities
of Quantum Chromodynamics. The penalty for achieving this perturbative picture
is the necessity of formulating the dynamics of QCD in light-front coordinates
and of dealing with the complexities of renormalization which such a
formulation entails. We describe the renormalization process first using a
qualitative phase space cell analysis, and we then set up a precise similarity
renormalization scheme with cutoffs on constituent momenta and exhibit
calculations to second order. We outline further computations that remain to be
carried out. There is an initial nonperturbative but nonrelativistic
calculation of the hadronic masses that determines the artificial potential,
with binding energies required to be fourth order in the coupling as in QED.
Next there is a calculation of the leading radiative corrections to these
masses, which requires our renormalization program. Then the real struggle of
finding the right extensions to perturbation theory to study the
strong-coupling behavior of bound states can begin.
</abstract>
