<date>
Tue, 18 Jul 2000 12:11:18 GMT
</date>

<title>
Field theory model giving rise to "quintessential inflation" without the
  cosmological constant and other fine tuning problems
</title>

<abstract>
  A field theory is developed based on the idea that the effective action of
yet unknown fundamental theory, at energy scale below M_{p} has the form of
expansion in two measures: S=\intd^{4}x[\Phi L_{1}+\sqrt{-g}L_{2}] where the
new measure \Phi is defined using the third-rank antisymmetric tensor. In the
new variables (Einstein frame) all equations of motion take canonical GR form
and therefore models are free of the well-known "defects" that distinguish the
Brans-Dicke type theories from GR. All novelty is revealed only in an unusual
structure of the effective potential U(\phi) and interactions which turns over
intuitive ideas based on our experience in field theory. E.g. the greater
\Lambda we admit in L_{2}, the smaller U(\phi) will be in the Einstein picture.
Field theory models are suggested with explicitly broken global continuos
symmetry which in the Einstein frame has the form \phi\to\phi+const. The
symmetry restoration occurs as \phi\to\infty. A few models are presented where
U is produced with the following shape: for \phi<-M_{p}, U has the form typical
for inflation model, e. g. U=\lambda\phi^4 with \lambda\sim 10^{-14};
for\phi>-M_{p}, U has mainly exponential form U\sim e^{-a\phi/M_{p}} with
variable a: a=14 for -M_{p}<\phi<M_{p} that admits nucleosynthesis; a=2 for
\phi>M_{p} that implies quintessence era. There is no need in any fine tuning
to prevent appearance of the CC term or any other terms that could violate
flatness of U at \phi\ggM_{p}. \lambda\sim 10^{-14} is obtained without fine
tuning as well. Quantized matter fields models, including gauge theories with
SSB can be incorporated without altering mentioned above results. Direct
fermion-inflaton coupling resembles Wetterich's model but it does not lead to
any observable effect at present. SSB does not raise any problem with CC.
</abstract>
