<date>
Tue, 4 Feb 1997 00:56:15 +0900 (JST)
</date>

<title>
Yangian Gelfand-Zetlin Bases, gl(N)-Jack Polynomials and computation of
  Dynamical Correlation Functions in the Spin Calogero-Sutherland Model
</title>

<abstract>
  We consider the gl(N)-invariant Calogero-Sutherland Models with N=1,2,3,...
in a unified framework, which is the framework of Symmetric Polynomials. By the
framework we mean an isomorphism between the space of states of the
gl(N)-invariant Calogero-Sutherland Model and the space of Symmetric Laurent
Polynomials. In this framework it becomes apparent that all gl(N)-invariant
Calogero-Sutherland Models are manifestations of the same entity, which is the
commuting family of Macdonald Operators. Macdonald Operators depend on two
parameters $q$ and $t$. The Hamiltonian of gl(N)-invariant Calogero-Sutherland
Model belongs to a degeneration of this family in the limit when both $q$ and
$t$ approach the N-th elementary root of unity. This is a generalization of the
well-known situation in the case of Scalar Calogero-Sutherland Model (N=1). In
the limit the commuting family of Macdonald Operators is identified with the
maximal commutative sub-algebra in the Yangian action on the space of states of
the gl(N)-invariant Calogero-Sutherland Model. The limits of Macdonald
Polynomials which we call gl(N)-Jack Polynomials are eigenvectors of this
sub-algebra and form Yangian Gelfand-Zetlin bases in irreducible components of
the Yangian action. The gl(N)-Jack Polynomials describe the orthogonal
eigenbasis of gl(N)-invariant Calogero-Sutherland Model in exactly the same way
as Jack Polynomials describe the orthogonal eigenbasis of the Scalar Model
(N=1). For each known property of Macdonald Polynomials there is a
corresponding property of gl(N)-Jack Polynomials. As a simplest application of
these properties we compute two-point Dynamical Spin-Density and Density
Correlation Functions in the gl(2)-invariant Calogero-Sutherland Model at
integer values of the coupling constant.
</abstract>
