<date>
Tue, 28 MAR 95 07:49:43 +0000
</date>

<title>
Extended Dualization: a method for the Bosonization of Anomalous Fermion
  Systems in Arbitrary Dimension
</title>

<abstract>
  The technique of extended dualization developed in this paper is used to
bosonize quantized fermion systems in arbitrary dimension $D$ in the low energy
regime. In its original (minimal) form, dualization is restricted to models
wherein it is possible to define a dynamical quantized conserved charge. We
generalize the usual dualization prescription to include systems with dynamical
non--conserved quantum currents. Bosonization based on this extended
dualization requires the introduction of an additional rank $0$ (scalar) field
together with the usual antisymmetric tensor field of rank $(D-2)$. Our
generalized dualization prescription permits one to clearly distinguish the
arbitrariness in the bosonization from the arbitrariness in the quantization of
the system. We study the bosonization of four--fermion interactions with large
mass in arbitrary dimension. First, we observe that dualization permits one to
formally bosonize these models by invoking the bosonization of the free massive
Dirac fermion and adding some extra model--dependent bosonic terms. Secondly,
we explore the potential of extended dualization by considering the particular
case of \underbar{chiral} four--fermion interactions. Here minimal dualization
is inadequate for calculating the extra bosonic terms. We demonstrate the
utility of extended dualization by successfully completing the bosonization of
this chiral model. Finally, we consider two examples in two dimensions which
illuminate the utility of using extended dualization by showing how
quantization ambiguities in a fermionic theory propagate into the bosonized
version. An explicit parametrization of the quantization ambiguities of the
chiral current in the Chiral Schwinger model is obtained. Similarly, for the
sine--Gordon interaction in the massive Thirring model the quantization
</abstract>
