<date>
Mon, 21 Jul 1997 19:54:18 -0400
</date>

<title>
Beyond Strings, Multiple Times and Gauge Theories of Area-Scalings
  Relativistic Transformations
</title>

<abstract>
  Nottale's special scale-relativity principle was proposed earlier by the
author as a plausible geometrical origin to string theory and extended objects.
Scale Relativity is to scales what motion Relativity is to velocities. The
universal, absolute, impassible, invariant scale under dilatations in Nature is
taken to be the Planck scale, which is not the same as the string scale.
Starting with ordinary actions for strings and other extended objects, we show
that gauge theories of volume-resolutions scale-relativistic symmetries, of the
world volume measure associated with the extended ``fuzzy'' objects, are a
natural and viable way to formulate the geometrical principle underlying the
theory of all extended objects. Gauge invariance can only be implemented if the
extendon actions in $D$ target dimensions are embedded in $D+1$ dimensions with
an extra temporal variable corresponding to the scaling dimension of the
original string coordinates. This is achieved upon viewing the extendon
coordinates, from the fuzzy worldvolume point of view, as noncommuting matrices
valued in the Lie algebra of Lorentz-scale relativistic transformations.
Preliminary steps are taken to merge motion relativity with scale relativity by
introducing the gauge field that gauges the Lorentz-scale symmetries in the
same vain that the spin connection gauges ordinary Lorentz transformations and,
in this fashion, one may go beyond string theory to construct the sought-after
General Theory of Scale-Motion Relativity. Such theory requires the
introduction of the scale-graviton (in addition to the ordinary graviton) which
is the field that gauges the symmetry which converts motion dynamics into
scaling-resolutions dynamics and vice versa (the analog of the gravitino that
gauges supersymmetry). To go beyond the quantum string geometry most probably
</abstract>
